<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
        <string name="app_name">yasen</string>
        <string name="bsm_alllah">Bism ellla el Rahman el Rahiem      yaaaaseeen     </string>
        <string name="press_to_next">press to see the next aya</string>
        <string name="sadak_alla_el3azem">sadak alla el aazem</string>
        <string name="ayat_2">By the wise Qur’ānِ</string>
        <string name="ayat_3"> Indeed you, [O Muḥammad], are from among the messengersَ</string>
        <string name="ayat_4">On a straight pathٍ</string>
        <string name="ayat_5"> [This is] a revelation of the Exalted in Might, the Merciful, </string>
        <string name="ayat_6">That you may warn a people whose forefathers were not warned, so they are unawareَ</string>
        <string name="ayat_7">Already the word [i.e., decree] has come into effect upon most of them, so they do not believeَ</string>
        <string name="ayat_8">Indeed, We have put shackles on their necks, and they are to their chins, so they are with heads [kept] aloftَ</string>
        <string name="ayat_9">And We have put before them a barrier and behind them a barrier and covered them, so they do not seeَ</string>
        <string name="ayat_10">And it is all the same for them whether you warn them or do not warn them - they will not believeَ</string>
        <string name="ayat_11"> You can only warn one who follows the message and fears the Most Merciful unseen. So give him good tidings of forgiveness and noble rewardٍ</string>
        <string name="ayat_12">Indeed, it is We who bring the dead to life and record what they have put forth and what they left behind, and all things We have enumerated in a clear registerٍ</string>
        <string name="ayat_13">And present to them an example: the people of the city, when the messengers came to itَ</string>
        <string name="ayat_14"> When We sent to them two but they denied them, so We strengthened [them] with a third, and they said, "Indeed, we are messengers to you."</string>
        <string name="ayat_15">They said, "You are not but human beings like us, and the Most Merciful has not revealed a thing. You are only telling lies."َ</string>
        <string name="ayat_16">They said, "Our Lord knows that we are messengers to you,َ</string>
        <string name="ayat_17">And we are not responsible except for clear notification</string>
        <string name="ayat_18">They said, "Indeed, we consider you a bad omen. If you do not desist, we will surely stone you, and there will surely touch you, from us, a painful punishment."</string>
        <string name="ayat_19">They said, "Your omen [i.e., fate] is with yourselves. Is it[1262] because you were reminded? Rather, you are a transgressing people."</string>
        <string name="ayat_20">َAnd there came from the farthest end of the city a man, running. He said, "O my people, follow the messengers</string>
        <string name="ayat_21">Follow those who do not ask of you [any] payment, and they are [rightly] guided َ</string>
        <string name="ayat_22">And why should I not worship He who created me and to whom you will be returned?َ</string>
        <string name="ayat_23"> Should I take other than Him [false] deities [while], if the Most Merciful intends for me some adversity, their intercession will not avail me at all, nor can they save me?ِ</string>
        <string name="ayat_24"> Indeed, I would then be in manifest error ٍ</string>
        <string name="ayat_25"> Indeed, I have believed in your Lord, so listen to meِ</string>
        <string name="ayat_26"> It was said, "Enter Paradise." He said, "I wish my people could knowَ</string>
        <string name="ayat_27">Of how my Lord has forgiven me and placed me among the honored َ</string>
        <string name="ayat_28">And We did not send down upon his people after him any soldiers from the heaven, nor would We have done soَ</string>
        <string name="ayat_29">It was not but one shout,[1264] and immediately they were extinguishedََ</string>
        <string name="ayat_30">How regretful for the servants. There did not come to them any messenger except that they used to ridicule him َ</string>
        <string name="ayat_31"> Have they not considered how many generations We destroyed before them - that they to them will not return? </string>
        <string name="ayat_32">And indeed, all of them will yet be brought present before Us َ</string>
        <string name="ayat_33"> And a sign for them is the dead earth. We have brought it to life and brought forth from it grain, and from it they eat </string>
        <string name="ayat_34">And We placed therein gardens of palm trees and grapevines and caused to burst forth therefrom some springs  </string>
        <string name="ayat_35"> That they may eat of His fruit.And their hands have not produced it,so will they not be grateful? َ</string>
        <string name="ayat_36"> Exalted is He who created all pairs - from what the earth grows and from themselves and from that which they do not know.َ</string>
        <string name="ayat_37"> And a sign for them is the night. We remove from it the [light of] day, so they are [left] in darkness </string>
        <string name="ayat_38">And the sun runs [on course] toward its stopping point. That is the determination of the Exalted in Might, the Knowing.ِ</string>
        <string name="ayat_39"> And the moon - We have determined for it phases, until it returns [appearing] like the old date stalk </string>
        <string name="ayat_40"> It is not allowable [i.e., possible] for the sun to reach the moon, nor does the night overtake the day, but each, in an orbit, is swimming </string>
        <string name="ayat_41"> And a sign for them is that We carried their forefathers in a laden ship. </string>
        <string name="ayat_42"> And We created for them from the likes of it that which they ride </string>
        <string name="ayat_43"> And if We should will, We could drown them; then no one responding to a cry would there be for them, nor would they be saved </string>
        <string name="ayat_44"> Except as a mercy from Us and provision for a time </string>
        <string name="ayat_45"> But when it is said to them, "Beware of what is before you and what is behind you; perhaps you will receive mercy. </string>
        <string name="ayat_46"> And no sign comes to them from the signs of their Lord except that they are from it turning away </string>
        <string name="ayat_47"> And when it is said to them, "Spend from that which Allāh has provided for you," those who disbelieve say to those who believe, "Should we feed one whom, if Allāh had willed, He would have fed? You are not but in clear error." </string>
        <string name="ayat_48"> And they say, "When is this promise, if you should be truthful?" </string>
        <string name="ayat_49"> They do not await except one blast which will seize them while they are disputing. </string>
        <string name="ayat_50"> And they will not be able [to give] any instruction, nor to their people can they return </string>
        <string name="ayat_51"> And the Horn will be blown;[For the second time, signaling the Resurrection] and at once from the graves to their Lord they will hasten </string>
        <string name="ayat_52"> They will say, "O woe to us! Who has raised us up from our sleeping place?" [The reply will be], "This is what the Most Merciful had promised, and the messengers told the truth." </string>
        <string name="ayat_53"> It will not be but one blast, and at once they are all brought present before Us.  </string>
        <string name="ayat_54">So today [i.e., the Day of Judgement] no soul will be wronged at all, and you will not be recompensed except for what you used to do.</string>
        <string name="ayat_55"> Indeed the companions of Paradise, that Day, will be amused in [joyful] occupation </string>
        <string name="ayat_56"> They and their spouses - in shade, reclining on adorned couches</string>
        <string name="ayat_57">For them therein is fruit, and for them is whatever they request [or wish]  </string>
        <string name="ayat_58"> [And] "Peace," a word from a Merciful Lord.</string>
        <string name="ayat_59"> [Then He will say], "But stand apart today, you criminals. </string>
        <string name="ayat_60"> Did I not enjoin upon you, O children of Adam, that you not worship Satan - [for] indeed, he is to you a clear enemy </string>
        <string name="ayat_61"> And that you worship [only] Me? This is a straight path </string>
        <string name="ayat_62"> And he had already led astray from among you much of creation, so did you not use reason? </string>
        <string name="ayat_63"> This is the Hellfire which you were promised. </string>
        <string name="ayat_64"> [Enter to] burn therein today for what you used to deny </string>
        <string name="ayat_65"> That Day, We will seal over their mouths, and their hands will speak to Us, and their feet will testify about what they used to earn.</string>
        <string name="ayat_66"> And if We willed, We could have obliterated their eyes, and they would race to [find] the path, and how could they see? </string>
        <string name="ayat_67">And if We willed, We could have deformed them, [paralyzing them] in their places so they would not be able to proceed, nor could they return.</string>
        <string name="ayat_68"> And he to whom We grant long life We reverse in creation;[1279] so will they not understand? </string>
        <string name="ayat_69"> And We did not give him [i.e., Prophet Muḥammad (ﷺ)] knowledge of poetry, nor is it befitting for him. It is not but a message and a clear Qur’ān  </string>
        <string name="ayat_70">To warn whoever is alive[1280] and justify the word [i.e., decree] against the disbelievers</string>
        <string name="ayat_71"> Do they not see that We have created for them from what Our hands[1281] have made, grazing livestock, and [then] they are their owners?  </string>
        <string name="ayat_72"> And We have tamed them for them, so some of them they ride, and some of them they eat. </string>
        <string name="ayat_73"> And for them therein are [other] benefits and drinks, so will they not be grateful? </string>
        <string name="ayat_74">But they have taken besides Allāh [false] deities that perhaps they would be helped </string>
        <string name="ayat_75">They are not able to help them, and they [themselves] are for them soldiers in attendance. </string>
        <string name="ayat_76"> So let not their speech grieve you. Indeed, We know what they conceal and what they declare. </string>
        <string name="ayat_77"> Does man not consider that We created him from a [mere] sperm-drop - then at once[1283] he is a clear adversary? </string>
        <string name="ayat_78"> And he presents for Us an example[1284] and forgets his [own] creation. He says, "Who will give life to bones while they are disintegrated?" </string>
        <string name="ayat_79"> Say, "He will give them life who produced them the first time; and He is, of all creation, Knowing."</string>
        <string name="ayat_80"> [It is] He who made for you from the green tree, fire, and then from it you ignite. </string>
        <string name="ayat_81"> Is not He who created the heavens and the earth Able to create the likes of them? Yes, [it is so]; and He is the Knowing Creator. </string>
        <string name="ayat_82"> His command is only when He intends a thing that He says to it, "Be," and it is. </string>
        <string name="ayat_83"> So exalted is He in whose hand is the realm of all things, and to Him you will be returned. </string>


    <string-array name="ayat_array">
            <item >@string/ayat_2</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_3</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_4</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_5</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_6</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_7</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_8</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_9</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_10</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_11</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_12</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_13</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_14</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_15</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_16</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_17</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_18</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_19</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_20</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_21</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_22</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_23</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_24</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_25</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_26</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_27</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_28</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_29</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_30</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_31</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_32</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_33</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_34</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_35</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_36</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_37</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_38</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_39</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_40</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_41</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_42</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_43</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_44</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_45</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_46</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_47</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_48</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_49</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_50</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_51</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_52</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_53</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_54</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_56</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_57</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_58</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_59</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_60</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_61</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_62</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_63</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_64</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_65</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_66</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_67</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_68</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_69</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_70</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_71</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_72</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_73</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_74</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_75</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_76</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_77</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_78</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_79</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_80</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_81</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_82</item>
            <item >@string/ayat_83</item>


    </string-array>


    </resources>

